---
layout: nil
---

<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title>Pixelnest Studio</title>

  <link href="http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity/rss.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity"/>

  <updated>{{ site.time | date_to_xmlschema }}</updated>
  <id>http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity</id>

<entry>
  <title>Install Unity and create your first scene</title>
  <link href="http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity/install-and-scene/" />
  <id>http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity/install-and-scene/</id>
  <content type="html">
	In this first chapter you will find some very basic informations: first, the download and installation of Unity, then the preparation of the first scene of our game.
  </content>
  <author>
	<name>Pixelnest Studio</name>
	<uri>http://pixelnest.io/about/</uri>
  </author>
</entry>
<entry>
  <title>Adding and displaying a background</title>
  <link href="http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity/background-and-camera/" />
  <id>http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity/background-and-camera/</id>
  <content type="html">
	Using the empty project we created in the previous part, we will now learn how to add a background and some fancy clouds.
  </content>
  <author>
	<name>Pixelnest Studio</name>
	<uri>http://pixelnest.io/about/</uri>
  </author>
</entry>
<entry>
  <title>Create a player and its enemies</title>
  <link href="http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity/player-and-enemies/" />
  <id>http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity/player-and-enemies/</id>
  <content type="html">
	In the previous chapter, we have added a background and some props to our scene. It is time to add some useful game elements, like the player!
  </content>
  <author>
	<name>Pixelnest Studio</name>
	<uri>http://pixelnest.io/about/</uri>
  </author>
</entry>
<entry>
  <title>Shooting (1/2)</title>
  <link href="http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity/shooting-1/" />
  <id>http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity/shooting-1/</id>
  <content type="html">
Our player ship is facing a terrifying Poulpi, but cannot do anything...

Let's grant him a weapon and some ammo! This will involve a bit more of scripting, but be confident. It worths it.
  </content>
  <author>
	<name>Pixelnest Studio</name>
	<uri>http://pixelnest.io/about/</uri>
  </author>
</entry>
<entry>
  <title>Shooting (2/2)</title>
  <link href="http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity/shooting-2/" />
  <id>http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity/shooting-2/</id>
  <content type="html">
	Our magnificent ship is now shooting innocent flying octopuses.

It can't stay that way. They need to respond. To shoot back. To fight for freedo... Oups. Sorry.

Using what we did in the last part, we will modify the enemy behavior so it can shoot projectiles too.
  </content>
  <author>
	<name>Pixelnest Studio</name>
	<uri>http://pixelnest.io/about/</uri>
  </author>
</entry>
<entry>
  <title>Parallax scrolling</title>
  <link href="http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity/parallax-scrolling/" />
  <id>http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity/parallax-scrolling/</id>
  <content type="html">
For the moment, we have created a static scene with a player and some enemies. It's a bit boring. Time to enhance our background and scene.

An effect that you find in every single 2D game for 15 years is "parallax scrolling".

To make it short, the idea is to move the background layers at different speeds (i.e., the farther the layer is, the slower it moves). If done correctly, this gives an illusion of depth. It's a cool, nice and easy-to-do effect.

Moreover, many shmups use a scrolling in one — or more — axis (except the original one, Space Invaders).

Let's implement that in Unity.
  </content>
  <author>
	<name>Pixelnest Studio</name>
	<uri>http://pixelnest.io/about/</uri>
  </author>
</entry>
<entry>
  <title>Playing with particles</title>
  <link href="http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity/particles/" />
  <id>http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity/particles/</id>
  <content type="html">
Our shooter is starting to have a good shape. It's time to enhance it a bit visually with particles.

Particles are (basically) simple sprites that will be repeated and displayed for a very short timespan.

Think about explosions, lasers, smokes, etc. Those are done with particles — most of the time (an explosion can be a simple animated sprite).

Unity provides a powerful built-in editor for particles with the Shuriken Engine. Let's see what we can do with it.
  </content>
  <author>
	<name>Pixelnest Studio</name>
	<uri>http://pixelnest.io/about/</uri>
  </author>
</entry>
<entry>
  <title>Making some noises on music</title>
  <link href="http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity/sounds/" />
  <id>http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity/sounds/</id>
  <content type="html">
Now that we have improved our game visually, with particles, we will add some sounds and a music in our project. It's very simple in Unity but it's still a very important part of a game.

You will learn where to find sounds and music, pick some, and play them in our game via a script.
  </content>
  <author>
	<name>Pixelnest Studio</name>
	<uri>http://pixelnest.io/about/</uri>
  </author>
</entry>
<entry>
  <title>Menus - loading and restarting the game</title>
  <link href="http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity/menus/" />
  <id>http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity/menus/</id>
  <content type="html">
We have finished our first level with a basic gameplay, some sounds, graphics and particles.

However, when the player dies, the game continues to run and it's impossible to start again. Moreover, when you launch it, you start directly. We are clearly in a situation where we need some menus to control the game.
  </content>
  <author>
	<name>Pixelnest Studio</name>
	<uri>http://pixelnest.io/about/</uri>
  </author>
</entry>
<entry>
  <title>Build, release and deploy</title>
  <link href="http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity/deployment/" />
  <id>http://pixelnest.io/tutorials/2d-game-unity/deployment/</id>
  <content type="html">
A short last part about how to do an executable that you can distribute. Short, because deploying with Unity is easy.
  </content>
  <author>
	<name>Pixelnest Studio</name>
	<uri>http://pixelnest.io/about/</uri>
  </author>
</entry>


</feed>
